This garden waters itself, and the
brain behind it costs seventeen pounds.
Most watering systems run on a
timer. They flood beds after rain
and leave them dry in a
heatwave, because a clock doesn't know
what the soil actually needs.
This one reads the soil instead.
A capacitive moisture sensor sits in
each bed, wired through an analogue-to-digital
board so the Pi can actually
understand it.
Every thirty minutes, the Pi checks
all five beds. Any bed below
its moisture target gets its valve
opened and the pump switched on,
one bed at a time.
It stops the moment the soil
is wet enough, or after a
safety timeout — whichever comes first.
No flooding, no guessing.
The whole thing runs off one
small solar panel, and it won
an engineering award for exactly this
reason.
Full build plans, parts list and
the actual code — link in
bio.